Matthew, Matthew 1.
The book of the genealogy of Jesus Christ, the son of David, the son of Abraham.
Abraham was the father of Isaac, and Isaac the father of Jacob, and Jacob the father
of Judah and his brothers, and Judah the father of Pires and Zerah by Tamar, and Pires the
father of Hezron, and Hezron the father of Ram, and Ram the father of Amminadab, and
Amminadab the father of Nashan, and Nashan the father of Salmon, and Salmon the father
of Boaz by Rahab, and Boaz the father of Obed by Ruth, and Obed the father of Jesse, and
Jesse the father of David the king.
And David was the father of Solomon by the wife of Uriah, and Solomon the father of Rehoboam,
and Rehoboam the father of Abijah, and Abijah the father of Asaph, and Asaph the father
of Jehoshaphat.
And Jehoshaphat the father of Joram, and Joram the father of Uzziah, and Uzziah the father
of Jotham, and Jotham the father of Ahaz, and Ahaz the father of Hezekiah, and Hezekiah
the father of Manasseh, and Manasseh the father of Amos, and Amos the father of Josiah, and
Josiah the father of Jeconiah and his brothers at the time of the deportation to Babylon.
And after the deportation to Babylon.
Jeconiah was the father of Shealtiel, and Shealtiel the father of Zerubbabel,
and Zerubbabel the father of Abiyud, and Abiyud the father of Eliakim,
and Eliakim the father of Azor, and Azor the father of Zadok,
and Zadok the father of Akim, and Akim the father of Eliud,
and Eliud the father of Eleazar, and Eleazar the father of Mathan,
and Mathan the father of Jacob, and Jacob the father of Joseph the husband of Mary.
of whom Jesus was born, who is called Christ. So all the generations from Abraham to David
were fourteen generations, and from David to the deportation to Babylon, fourteen generations,
and from the deportation to Babylon to the Christ, fourteen generations.
Now the birth of Jesus Christ took place in this way. When his mother Mary had been betrothed to
Joseph, before they came together she was found to be with child from the Holy Spirit,
and her husband Joseph, being a just man and unwilling to put her to shame, resolved to
divorce her quietly. But as he considered these things, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared to
him in a dream, saying, Joseph, son of David, do not fear to take Mary as your wife, for that which
is conceived in her is from the Holy Spirit. She will bear a son,
and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.
All this took place to fulfill what the Lord had spoken by the prophet.
Behold, the virgin shall conceive and bear a son, and they shall call his name Emmanuel.
Which means, God with us. When Joseph woke from sleep, he did as the angel of the Lord
commanded him. He took his wife, but knew her not until she had given birth to a son.
He called his name Jesus.
So
he called his wife, and she called his name Emmanuel, and he called his name Jesus.